Homework can wait. The city can't.
Spider-Man: Homecoming is a action, adventure, science
fiction film directed by Jon Watts.
Following the events of Captain America: Civil War, Peter Parker, with the help of his mentor Tony Stark, tries to balance his life as an ordinary high
school student in Queens, New York City, with fighting crime as his superhero alter ego Spider-Man as a new threat, the Vulture, emerges.
Peter Parker / Spider-Man, played by Tom Holland.
Adrian Toomes / Vulture, played by Michael Keaton.
Tony Stark / Iron Man, played by Robert Downey Jr..
May Parker, played by Marisa Tomei.
Happy Hogan, played by Jon Favreau.
Pepper Potts, played by Gwyneth Paltrow.
Spider-Man: Homecoming is a 2017 American superhero film based on the Marvel Comics character Spider-Man, produced by
Columbia Pictures, Marvel Studios, and Pascal Pictures, and distributed by Sony Pictures Releasing.
It is the second Spider-Man film reboot and the 16th film
in the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU).
The film was directed by Jon Watts from a screenplay by the writing teams of Jonathan Goldstein and
John Francis Daley, Watts and Christopher Ford, and Chris McKenna and Erik Sommers.
Tom Holland stars as Peter Parker / Spider-Man, alongside Michael Keaton, Jon Favreau, Gwyneth Paltrow, Zendaya, Donald Glover,
Jacob Batalon, Laura Harrier, Tony Revolori, Bokeem Woodbine, Tyne Daly, Marisa Tomei, and Robert Downey Jr.
In the film, Parker tries to balance high school life with being
Spider-Man while facing the Vulture (Keaton).
In February 2015, Marvel Studios and Sony reached a deal to share the film rights
for Spider-Man, integrating the character into the established MCU.
The following June, Holland was cast as the title
character, and Watts was hired to direct.
This was followed shortly by the hiring of Daley and Goldstein.
In April 2016, the film's title was revealed, along with additional cast,
including Downey in his MCU role of Tony Stark / Iron Man.
Principal photography began in June 2016 at Pinewood Atlanta Studios in Fayette
County, Georgia, and continued in Atlanta, Los Angeles, and New York City.
The other screenwriters were revealed during filming,
which concluded in Berlin in October 2016.
The production team made efforts to differentiate the
film from previous Spider-Man films.
Spider-Man: Homecoming premiered in Hollywood, Los Angeles, on June 28, 2017, and was
released in the United States on July 7, as part of Phase Three of the MCU.
Homecoming grossed $880.9 million worldwide, becoming the
second-most-successful Spider-Man film and the sixth-highest-grossing film of 2017.
It received praise for the light tone, its focus on Parker's high school
life, and the performances, particularly of Holland and Keaton.
Two sequels have been released: Spider-Man: Far From Home
(2019) and Spider-Man: No Way Home (2021).
A new trilogy of live-action films from Sony and
Marvel Studios is in development.
The film explores themes of high school, new york city,
washington dc, usa, secret identity, superhero.
The tone is thought_provoking.